Some guys just can't handle Vegas.
The Hangover is a comedy film directed by Todd Phillips.
When three friends finally come to after a raucous night of bachelor-party
revelry, they find a baby in the closet and a tiger in the bathroom.
But they can't seem to locate their best friend, Doug –
who's supposed to be tying the knot.
Launching a frantic search for Doug, the trio perseveres through a
nasty hangover to try to make it to the church on time.
Phil Wenneck, played by Bradley Cooper.
Stu Price, played by Ed Helms.
Alan Garner, played by Zach Galifianakis.
Doug Billings, played by Justin Bartha.
Jade, played by Heather Graham.
Tracy Garner, played by Sasha Barrese.
The Hangover is a 2009 American comedy film directed by Todd
Phillips, and written by Jon Lucas and Scott Moore.
It is the first installment in The Hangover trilogy.
The film stars Bradley Cooper, Ed Helms, Zach Galifianakis,
Heather Graham, Justin Bartha, and Jeffrey Tambor.
It tells the story of Phil Wenneck (Cooper), Stu Price (Helms), Alan Garner (Galifianakis), and Doug Billings
(Bartha), who travel to Las Vegas for a bachelor party to celebrate Doug's impending marriage.
However, Phil, Stu, and Alan wake up with Doug missing and no memory of the previous
night's events, and must find Doug before the wedding can take place.
Lucas and Moore wrote the script after executive producer Chris Bender's friend
disappeared and had a large bill after being sent to a strip club.
After Lucas and Moore sold it to the studio for $2 million, Phillips and Jeremy Garelick rewrote the script to include a
tiger as well as a subplot involving a baby and a police cruiser, and also including boxer Mike Tyson.
Filming took place in Nevada for 15 days, and during filming, the three main
actors (Cooper, Helms, and Galifianakis) formed a real friendship.
The Hangover was produced by Legendary Pictures, Green Hat
Films and BenderSpink and released by Warner Bros.
Pictures on June 5, 2009, and was a critical and commercial success.
The film became the tenth-highest-grossing film of 2009,
with a worldwide gross of over $467 million.
The film won the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture –
Musical or Comedy, and received multiple other accolades.
It became the highest-grossing R-rated comedy ever in the United States, surpassing
a record previously held by Beverly Hills Cop for almost 25 years.
The film was followed by two sequels: The Hangover Part II
(2011) and The Hangover Part III (2013).
Both were commercial successes, but neither were well-received critically.
The film explores themes of blackjack, stag night, lost
weekend, chapel, hit with tire iron.
The tone is lighthearted.